POOJA JEEVA

(857) 316-6801 • poojajeevaa@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/poojajeeva/

OBJECTIVE

Dynamic, solution-oriented marketing professional with 6+ years of progressive experience within B2B and B2C industries, specializing in product marketing, go-to-market (GTM) strategy, digital strategy, and brand development with track record of delivering measurable results, having generated over \$15M in revenue across multiple industries and managing advertising budget exceeding \$100K per month.

KEY STRENGTHS

- Marketing Platforms: Adobe Suite (InDesign, Illustrator, Photoshop), Canva, ActiveCampaign, Mailchimp, Constant Contact
- Analytics & Reporting: Google Analytics (Universal + GA4), Google Tag Manager, Looker Studio, Power BI, SQL, Excel, R
- SEO & SEM Tools: SEMrush, Google Keyword Planner
- Project Management: Monday.com, Asana, Jira/Confluence
- AI tools: Claude, ChatGPT, Grok, Jasper, Perplexity

EXPERIENCE

Product Marketing Manager

Sep 2024 - Present

- Designed and launched product-centric and educational email marketing campaigns to drive website lead generation, integrating advanced copywriting, visual design, and HTML coding techniques
- Elevated brand visibility by boosting organic impressions by and driving a increase in organic clicks through robust onpage and backend SEO methods
- Supported channel partnerships as primary POC, managing co-branded collateral creation, securing new strategic partner agreements and contributing to the onboarding of sales reps

Associate Product Marketing Manager

June 2023 - Aug 2024

- Established Product Marketing department for 4 B2B IT units, conducted competitive analysis, identified and bridged interdepartmental gaps, developed content strategies, securing AI web experience contract
- Identified needs of sales team, built sales enablement toolkit (battle cards, demo scripts & case studies) integrated into Salesforce
- Crafted bi-weekly whitepaper campaigns, lifting email open rates and lead generation for new tech products in 6 months

Product Marketing Consultant

Aug 2023 - Jan 2024

- Managed cross-functional stakeholders for 5 virtual events, leveraging market insights to secure in corporate sponsorships
- event budget using Excel with Cube, achieving cost savings via vendor negotiations and resource allocation
- Orchestrated sponsorship fulfillment for partners, coordinating and aligning funding with key initiatives to maximize impact

Marketing and Strategy Analyst (Co-op)

Feb 2023 - May 2023

- Optimized SaaS sales funnel via targeted SFMC campaigns and buyer-specific content, reducing lead response time by
- Managed vendor relationships for a renewable energy client, optimizing in research budgets and improving market through detailed competitor analysis positioning by
- Designed real-time KPI dashboards in PowerBI for 5 co-sponsored 'Future of AI' events, engaging target pre-ipo founders Sep 2021 - Feb 2023

Marketing Research Analyst

- Analyzed 5000+ data points via market research, resulting in 1 new program offering and a rise in cross-program enrollment
- Elevated program enrollment rates by through targeted SFMC email campaigns, while increasing social media engagement across LinkedIn, Instagram, and Twitter by

Fractional Product Marketing Consultant

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

- over 3 months by conducting primary research with 2000+ members to enhance UX features Increased mobile bookings by
- Developed insight-driven newsletters that resulted in increase in loyalty program sign-ups through targeted member communications

Product Marketing Specialist

Jun 2019 - Jul 2021

- Led product-led growth strategy, boosting customer engagement by with 500+ client insights & field marketing events
- Implemented SEO strategy to optimize product pages with improved keyword targeting and technical specifications

EDUCATION

Suffolk University - Sawyer Business School Boston, MA

Madras University - M.O.P Vaishnav College Chennai, IN